hi this is step and welcome to my
channel in this channel we talked about
personal finance productivity and
adulting in general so if you're
interested in this topics please
subscribe to this channel hit the
notification Bell like this video and
share this to your
[Music]
friends in my previous video I discussed
about Sun Life assur so term insurance
from sunlife so if you're
interested so it is an affordable
insurance from sunlife that you may want
to consider and in this video I also
promis to discuss about another
insurance from sunlight which is called
sunfit and well but disclaimer I am not
an insurance agent or a financial
advisor insurance from sunlight so
insurance is term insurance which is
sunlife assure and the other one is
itong sunfit and well so sunfit and well
is a bit more comprehensive compared to
Sun Life assure so in this video I will
discuss the key features of sunfit andw
just
in I also mentioned in my previous
video life
insurance death benefits just like the
term insurance or the Sun Life
assure investment component but the
investment or the return is fluctuating
SOA
cash benefits at the end of certain
period fixed AMS or endowment so one
example of that is sunfit and well so
sunfit and well is not a v because the
return is not fluctuating fixed amount
at a certain period so comprehensive
life and health insurance coverage
insurance is up to age 100 and then
critical illness protection so critical
illness guys covered is 114 critical
illness and it is categorized into major
critical illness minor critical illness
and specific cancer condition so
comprehensive tala sunfit and well and
then guaranteed cash benefits so as
early as age 65 you may Advance
5% of your policy space amount so for
example you amount policy MO is 1
million so you can advance 5% of it so
that's 50,000 starting age 65 for up to
8 consecutive years so 65 to
73a 65 + 8 so 73 up to age
73 receive 50,000 per year may not be
too much for some at least receive cash
guaranteed cash benefits and and as to
the life insurance protection for
example your dependence will receive um
death benefits equivalent to the face
amount of your
policy decrease if
ever benefit critical
illness cover critical illness for major
and minor critical illness and specific
cancer condition so for example in your
lifetime just in case critical illness
so
am face amount policy
so amount receive beneficiaries if
ever another key feature of sunfit and
well is the special bonus and dividend
earnings so this is different from the
guaranteed cash benefits mention so
special bonus and dividends earning you
may receive this at the end of the
premium paying period and amount depend
ending on sun life's investment
performance so premium paying period
sunfit and well limited pay
comprehensive plan it so you can pay for
10 years or 20 years and you will be
covered up to age 100 so sunit and well
and then the mode of
payment semiannual annual quarterly but
you can save if you pay it anual now I
want to focus on the critical illness
condition so Health protection so Sun
fit unwell provides benefits in case you
are diagnosed with any of the 114
covered critical conditions so you 114
critical illness it is subdivided into
minor and major stages so you covered
for 64 major critical illnesses 34 minor
critical illnesses and then 16 specific
cancer
conditions covered major or Min or
critical illness and then specific
cancer conditions
so so major critical illness you are
entitled to benefits equivalent to 100%
of the original pH amount if diagnosed
majoral
illness
ill of
course amount minor critical illness
before
so
100% major critical illness so it's
already deducted and minor critical
illness for example Minal
illness
100%
am it's only 20% of the original phas
amount or 1 million whichever is lower
and then specific condition if ever you
have undergone angioplasty or invasive
treatment for coronary artery disease so
if you are only entitled for 10% of the
original pH amount or 400,000 pesos
whichever is lower and then specific
cancer booster so you are entitled 50%
of the original pH amount in addition to
the critical illness benefit if the life
insured is diagnosed for the first time
of the 16 specific cancer conditions so
for example if you are diagnosed with
lung cancer this is a major critical
illness so aside from the 100% critical
illness major critical illness the
benefit you are also entitled for an
additional 50% of the amount of the
policy so
coverage
canc so for fever
BREC major critical illness so you are
supposed to be entitled 100% of the
amount of your policies for example 1
million but since included in specific
cancer illness so you are also entitled
for the benefit of the specific cancer
booster so that would be another 50% of
the face amount of your policy so total
all in
all claim is 1.5 million so I suggest
guys if
ever sunfit and
well conditions terms
covered cooling off period or grace
period considered enforce policies so 15
days as to death benefits if ever
critical illness benefit so 100% claim
insurance but previously if you have
claimed for any minor critical illness
benefit or major critical illness
benefit or endowments receive deduct
amount policy so receive beneficiaries
if you die I know guys I've mentioned
this in my previous video Sun lifee
assure regarding critical illness so
make sure now if you sign up for an
insurance or sign up for the form be
honest information oral history because
it can affect your claims in the future
so approve request if ever critical
within 90 days from the approval of your
policy or enforce policy
so 90 days I also want to discuss the
supplementary benefits of this plan guys
so you have accidental death benefits so
just in case Nam due to
accident receive additional
benefits dependents or beneficiaries and
then you can also add total disability
benefit so if ever you had a dis
ability so your premiums are
waved
enfor premiums due to disability and
then Hospital income benefits so this
provides a fixed amount of daily cash
benefit in case of the insured
hospitalization so if ever admit Ka
Hospital you can claim this one but I
think condition is 3 days or
more ad
Hospital Avil benefit Hospital income
benefit and then this supplementary
benefits is not mandatory
so basic policy but remember that your
premiums will increase if supplementary
benefits so it's up to you I will show
you a proposal a sample proposal C
paraa he was 27 years old at that time
and then is 20 years premium paying
period and then the the amount of the
coverage is 1 million pesos but
then supplementary benefits so for this
basic policy basic plan benefit suppl
benefits accidental death Hospital
income benefits so the annual premium
for a 1 million face amount is 28,3
60 so that is annual if ever suppl
benefits it's possible or amount premium
and then we will pay this premium annual
premium for the next 20 years and after
20 years stop payment annual premium but
then the benefits will be up to 100
years old so until age 100 so coverage
and then guaranteed cash benefits so
when my husband reached age 65
so claim guaranteed cash benefits which
is
5% of 1 million so that's 50,000 per
year for the next 8 years so up to age
73 so guys if ever at age
80 critical illness major hopefully not
so just an example if ever critical
illness major
major critical illness you can claim
100% of the face amount so supposedly G
if ever claim cash benefits
am face
amount cover major critical illness if
ever at age 18 major critical illness so
anything amount from your cash benefits
or endowments or dividend or bonuses
educt if
ever time you need to claim for critical
illness or death benefits so I think y
Lang Naman guys you sunfit and well it's
comprehensive compared to Sun Life
assure it's more
comprehensive critical illness
coverage sopr
if ever critical
illness shoulder or covered insurance
policy critical illness and one of the
reason is that major critical illness
minor so in this case sunfit and well
covered major and minor critical illness
although minor
100% at
least so at
least although we don't hope
claim insurance we hope to be healthy
just in case hopefully not at
least so that's it guys I hope you
learned a lot from this video please
comment down below if questions I'll try
to answer and
again term insurance from sunlife which
is called sunlife assure you can watch
that video must affordable sh life
insurance if
Everet thank you so much guys for
watching see you again in my next videos
bye do not forget to like comment and
subscribe see you